navigraph.com 2009-11-02

# Navigraph

## The Information We Collect from You via the Web Browser

When you enter the website we register the following information about you: 

  * IP number
  * Browser make and version
  * Browser language settings
  * Operating system make and version
  * The address of the webpage that sent you to our website, if any

Also, as soon as you establish a connection between your browser and our server we create a number for you, a so called session ID, and place it in your computer's primary memory as a temporary cookie. This number is sent to the server at each call from the client as a mean of identification.

## What We Do with the Information We Collect from You via the Web Browser?

We collect the information listed above to better understand our visitors and to adapt the website so that it displays correctly for all software used to browse it. The information cannot be directly linked to you or your personal details. Note however that the IP number can be sent to your Internet Service Provider (ISP) to obtain your invoice address if we suspect that a crime has been committed. This usually requires a court subpoena however and is preceded by several legal procedures

Although we can see the specific browser make for a certain visitor, this information is generally treated in aggregated form. Most of the time we are interested in knowing how many of our visitors that have a certain make and version of their browser, or to see how effective our marketing actions have been at a particular website.

The session ID is used to identify you. The HTTP protocol that transmits webpages is stateless. This means that one call to the server is independent from the previous one. To recall that it was you and your browser that once successfully passed the authentication procedure using your user name and password, the server needs to link you with a session. It does this by using this session ID. If you prevent temporary cookies to be stored, by altering your firewall settings or browser connectivity settings, this ID will not be passed and the Navigraph website login features will not work as intended. You will receive a -999 error.

According to the Swedish law “Lag (2003:389) om elektronisk kommunikation” which entered into force 25th July 2003 you have now been duly informed that this website uses cookies, and that we use them for remembering your authentication procedure, and that you may turn them off but with the consequence that you will not be able to log in

By now you probably think that we are extracting an awful lot of information from you. We can assure you that this is no more and no less than what ordinary professional websites do. The difference is that here we have explained in depth what it is we do and how we treat the information we collect. We hope that by explaining to you how our procedures work, you will have confidence in us and trust us with your business. 

## The Information You Give Us via the Web Browser

When you register a user profile with us we ask you to provide the following set of data: 

  * First and last nameFirst and last name
  * E-mail address
  * Country of origin
  * Credit card details
  * Coupon ID

## What We Do with the Information You Give Us via the Web Browser?

By providing us with the information above your actions are interpreted as your consent for us to store first and last name, e-mail address, and country of origin (not credit card details, see below).

The first and last name are generally used to give you a personalized greeting when you log on to your account and when you receive a newsletter. It is also useful for our support staff to have a name to call you by. Although your user name or 32 character unique identifier would suffice, this world is such a nicer place if we have a first name to call each other by.

The e-mail address is used to send you important messages relating to your user account status. These messages are important and therefore we ask you to verify your e-mail address by clicking the activation link we send you upon registration so that we know that you are receiving our notices.

The country of origin is used to control language settings in various interfaces. It is also used to calculate certain functions that has to do with tax regulations.

The credit card details you provide are entered into an interface which communicates with our Credit Card Interface Service Provider (CCISP). The name of the CCISP is Censeo, [www.censeo.se](http://www.censeo.se/). The communication between your browser and the CCISP server is secured by SSL which is an industry standard encryption technique for communication over the HTTPS protocol.

Towards the end of your purchase the CCISP servers call back to the Navigraph servers to confirm that they payment was successfully processed. This call does not contain any sensitive information so it may be done over unencrypted HTTP. Some browsers alert the user when changing from HTTPS to HTTP and some of our users feel uneasy when this happens. We will install a SSL-certificate on our server as well, to prevent these misunderstandings, but you may rest assured that all transactions made involving your credit card details are just as safe as at any other website using industry standard SSL-encryption.

Your credit card details are not stored with us. All we see is whether the transaction is OK or not, and if so, which ID the transaction has in the CCISP database. This means that no Navigraph staff member could ever see your credit card details. More importantly, our database does not contain your credit card details which greatly reduces the potential damage in the case of a successful hacker attack.

The coupon ID is a 26 character combination which you enter and exchange for an amount of credits. The 26 characters tell us where you have bought your coupon, when you bought it (and subsequently when it expires), your order ID with the vendor and a checksum to make sure all of the information provided has not been obfuscated. Some vendors send us a confirmation e-mail on the side or your order with them. By linking the order ID with the information in this e-mail we have the possibility to find out additional data that you might have filed with your vendor. To know exactly which data this is, you must consult the privacy statement of the vendor in question, or contact the support department of that vendor.

We do not use the coupon ID for anything else but checking the validity of the credits associated and that the vendor that issued the coupon is an authorized one.

You may view and change your information by logging in to the protected user area of the website. Here you can also set your preferences if you would like to receive newsletters from us. According to the Swedish law “Personuppgiftslag (1998:204)” you may also write us to have these changes made, alternatively have your account and associated personal information deleted.

We only use your personal information to fulfill our obligations to serve our users. Any questions regarding this may be sent via post services as a signed written request to: 

Navigraph  
Att: Personuppgiftsansvarige  
P.O. Box 2052  
SE-600 02 NORRKOPING  
SWEDEN

## The Information You Give Us via the nDAC Software

Only user name and password is sent via the nDAC software. It checks to see if you are a registered user and what your credit balance is. Then it returns a special sequence of numbers and characters to register your local copy.

As you use your nDAC software it calls our server to ask for data. We log the data you request.

## What We Do with the Information You Give Us via the nDAC Software?

We use this data to check that you have a valid license with us. We also use it to charge you for the data you download. Finally we use it to see which data that is more popular than other. We might pass on the information regarding e.g. the 10 top most popular airports to some of our partners for them to develop products which obviously has the most interest.

The nDAC software does not send any information about your computer system to us. It contains no spyware.

## The Information You Give Us via the Data You Download

Some of the data you download from us has been watermarked with information that can be associated with you. This means that if you copy and share Navigraph data, the distributed copy can be traced back to you since the watermark is uniquely created for you.

## What Do we Do with the Information You Give Us via the Data You Download?

This data is intended to give us some protection against piracy and illegal use of our products and services. When we see your data where it should not be, according to conditions in the terms of service, we terminate your user account and confiscate your remaining credits. We may also pursue legal actions to claim financial compensation for the damages you caused.

## Do We Share the Information We Collect?

Sometimes we offer our partners to send you information. In these cases the partner gives us the information to send and we issue the newsletter. This means that your name and e-mail address is never passed on to any third party.

Sometimes we give your usage pattern to our partners so that they can better adapt their products to fit your needs. This information is however always aggregated and never relates to you personally.

If you place and order with us for a product that is delivered by a partner or vendor, we might ask you for additional information such as shipping address. This information is passed on to the partner or vendor so that they can complete your order. It might be that they store this information for reference. You may receive newsletters or other promotional information from them. In this case, you are usually provided with an account with them so that you can turn this option off, but in fact it is all up to the local laws of the country where the partner or vendor resides.

However, if we were to be acquired by another company, this company would come in possession of the user database. In any case, they could not use your data in any other fashion that according to the terms which you already agreed to, namely those in the privacy statement.

Finally, if local laws or regulations require us to share our logs with authorities we are obliged to do so. But, in short, we only serve your interests and would never compromise your personal information.
